There is something that I've coined,
and it's called the fist bump effect.
For so many of you,
when it comes to content, strategy,
ideation, whatever,
you seem to miss the point. For instance,
I know you as personal trainers a lot.
They seem to think people want to see
their lunch, their workout, and their abs.
I can tell you,
no one cares about any of those things.
What you are trying to do on social media,
whether you are a breathwork coach, an
accountant, financial advisor, you
are trying to give people so many
amazing bits of information to solve their
problems, that should they
see you somewhere,
they will feel inclined to give you a fist
bump.
Maybe the butcher's,
maybe the supermarket,
maybe even at Thorpe Park.
"Hey, bro,
your content has really helped me get
through my business.
Give it here, champ."
And you just got to ask yourself,
you just go back and look
through your last 30, 40, 50 videos.
Are you going to get
that reaction from someone?
Now, one of the issues you have is
if you're too much of a clown,
you're just there
to entertain people and make them laugh.
[chuckles] "Bro, your content's so funny,
man." I've even had this before
where people are like, "Oh, bro,
I love it when you call people out, man."
And I'm like, "Oof. Yeah, cool. Is
that paying the bills?" When I meet
someone and they're like, "Oh,
your books changed my life," I'm like,
[cash register sound] £1 royalty per book.
Come on.
And then when people see me and go, "Oh,
I'm in your business mentorship.
You've really helped my business." Again,
there are different levels of fist bump,
but ultimately, even
if it's the £1 royalty I'm getting from
one of my books.
Whether it's thousands of dollars I get
from mentoring, or whether it's the
education empowerment I'm giving someone
from calling out a creatine gummy brand.
Ultimately,
I want to collect a lot of fist bumps
because the fist bump to me
is a physical manifestation of an
accruance.
That's just a word I've made up.
An amount of goodwill that you
are generating
between you and your audience because your
shirtless selfies at a HYROX tournament
are not generating goodwill.
You taking pictures of your lunch,
you're not accruing
goodwill,
and you telling us your word of the day,
which no one cares about, is not
accruing goodwill.
You need to solve people's problems to the
point that they find
you fist bump effect. Now,
I coined this something else in my most
recent business event,
and what I want you to do
is think of it like a massive
pyramid in front of you. See.
Only the top 2% of people in your
audience are going to buy your stuff.
Great way to think about it.
So now you know that
if you want 10 clients,
you need to teach 1,000
people enough information to give you a
fist bump.
If you want to have 200 clients
or 2,000 clients,
you realize the infinite scale
of people that you need to give you a fist
bump, knowing that the majority of them
would happily say,
"I love your content,"
and still never buy your stuff.
I used to work in a gym in the UK,
and I'm going to be big-headed.
I've done pretty well as a personal
trainer in the UK.
You could argue the most successful.
You could.
There could be some other metrics.
You could say, "Oh,
Sean Casey made more than you on a PDF of
a recipe
book." He did.
Joe Wicks sold more cookbooks.
He also did.
But I was a proper personal trainer.
Fitness first, gym in Bracknell.
I actually did the reps and the sets.
I didn't run a boot camp.
I didn't have a team.
You could throw out there,
or at least top three.
Went into the gym handing out free cans of
Nutonic, and the guy behind it was like,
"Mate,
big fan." "Hi." "Love your stuff." "Thank
you." I go, "Have
a can of Nutonic." He goes,
"Always wanted to try one of these."
"What?"
I said, "You've never tried one?" He goes,
"No." I went, "Hater. Hater.
You're in the gym
that I've managed to escape velocity from.
I managed to do all the things
that you want to do in your career.
You've never even tried my drink, bro.
There's a can of White Monster on the
bloody table." And what I'm getting to the
point of that is there
are two things here, two worlds colliding.
There are so many people
that would give you a fist bump
when your content's right,
but still only a minuscule amount of them
are going to do content with you.
So if you do not generate
that goodwill through solving people's
problems, which
may I add,
live within your existing client base.
Even if you're only working with six
clients,
every time they ask you something,
that's a bit of content. Ding, ding, ding.
If you just continually turn up on the
internet and solve those problems every
single day, you will grow
that audience of fist bumpers,
and then you can skim the
top 1% to 2% as clients.
And there's probably the best audit you
could
do of your social media right now.
Watch your own content and go,
"Is this fist
bump worthy?" If not,
you've got some work to do.
Now, if you are a personal trainer
and you're starting out, I did create a
blueprint so you can understand how to
make your first 100K in a year.
So get those fist bumps in,
then watch this video.
Just going to take you to the next level.
Thanks for watching.